Finding Aid for the Edward C. Weber Papers, 1949-2005
Edward C. Weber Papers
- Correspondence
  - Turnbull, Richard C. (reference: 1907 IWW strike in Portland, OR) (Box 47)
  - Turner, Jean-Rae (reference: IWW photos for book on Passaic County, NJ) (Box 47)
  - Turning Point (Brooklyn, NY) (Box 47)
  - Tuttle, Carlson (re: loaning to LC of Lawrence Gracia manuscripts – not found in MIRLYN) (Box 47)
  - Twavay (Dominica) (Box 47)
  - Tyler, Robert (reference: technocracy movement; IWW; Howard Scott) (Box 47)
  - Tyson, David B. (reference: Misc. microfilm #2 containing Fair Play, Firebrand, Liberty Library) (Box 47)
  - UFAHAMU (Los Angeles, CA) (Box 47)
  - Ulrick, John (reference: wants political cartoons digitized and put online for his web page) (Box 47)
  - Uhuru (Montreal, Quebec) (Box 47)
  - Ukranian-American (New York, NY) (Box 47)
  - Ukranian Quarterly (New York, NY) (Box 47)
  - Umanita Nova (Rome, Italy) (Box 47)
  - Umbra (New York, NY) (Box 47)
  - Umbral (Paris, France) (Box 47)
  - Uncommon Books (Box 47)
  - Underground (New York, NY) (Box 47)
  - Underground Press Syndicate (Box 47)
  - Union Democracy in Action (New York, NY) (Box 47)
  - Union des Groupes Anarchistes-Communistes (Paris, France) (Box 47)
  - Union W.A.G.E. (Berkeley, CA) (Box 47)
  - United Federation of Teachers (Box 47)
  - United Front Press, Inc. (San Francisco, CA) (Box 47)
  - United Klans of America (Tuscaloosa, Alabama) (Box 47)
  - United Mine Workers of America (reference: 100th anniversary celebration) (Box 47)
  - United States Information Services (USIS) (LC request for Grenada publications) (Box 47)
  - U.S. President’s Committee on Migratory Labor (LC request for Migratory Labor Notes) (Box 47)
  - United World Federalists (Box 47)
  - Unity (San Francisco, CA) (League of revolutionary Struggle, M-L) (Box 47)
  - Unity and Struggle (Newark, NJ) (Box 47)
  - University Centers for Rational Alternatives, Inc. (Box 47)
  - University Microfilms (Box 47)
  - University of California, Berkeley, Library (re: starting a social protest research collection) (Box 47)
  - University of California, Berkeley, Regional Oral History Office (Box 47)
  - University of California, Los Angeles, Institute for Social Science Research (re: starting an immigration research collection) (Box 47)
  - University of California, Los Angeles, Library (re: order for copy of Police Malpractice and the Watts Riot) (Box 47)
  - University of California, San Diego (reference: Lois Orr Papers; Spanish Civil War materials) (Box 47)
  - University of Cincinnati (John J. and James B. McNamara Papers) (Box 47)
  - University of Connecticut (re: Collectors Network) (Box 47)
  - University of Illinois, Institute of Labor and Industrial Relations (Box 47)
  - University of Illinois Library (letter to Harriet Jameson) (Box 47)
  - University of Kansas, Wilcox Collection of Contemporary Political Movements (Box 47)
  - University of Michigan, Institute for Social Research (re: donation of French Parliamentary Surveys) (Box 47)
  - University of Michigan Language Laboratory (re: converting audio tapes) (Box 47)
  - University of Minnesota (re: donation of right wing materials) (Box 47)
  - University of Minnesota, Immigration History Research Center (Box 47)
  - University of Missouri, Labor Education Program (reference: list of active labor history archives) (Box 47)
  - University of Saskatchewan (re: request of Edmund SantaVicca’s bibliography) (Box 47)
  - University of Utah Press (reference: biography of Joe Hill; need permissions) (Box 47)
  - University of Washington Libraries (Box 47)
  - University of Wisconsin Library, Green Bay (reference: Leon Kramer) (Box 47)
  - University of Wisconsin Library, Madison (Box 47)
  - University Place Book Shop (Box 47)
  - Unveiling Cuba (New York, NY) (letters from ECW re: Cuba and Castro) (Box 47)
  - Up Against the Wall Street Journal (Box 47)
  - Up From the Bottom (San Diego, CA) (Box 47)
  - Up from Under (New York, NY) (Box 47)
  - Update (San Diego) (Box 47)
  - Upfront America (Houston, TX) (Box 47)
  - UPSurge (Louisville, KY) (Box 47)
  - Urban Guerrilla, The (TUG) (San Francisco, CA) (Box 48)
  - U.S.A. Magazine (New York, NY) (Box 48)
  - USSF (United States Servicemen’s Fund) (re: subscription to About Face) (Box 48)
  - Utas, I. L. (re: donation of materials) (Box 48)
  - V.E.P. News (Voter Education Project) (Box 48)
  - V.O.H. (Voice of Hope Publishing) (Box 48)
  - Valk, Annie (reference: lesbians and gays in the post WWII period) (Box 48)
  - Vallvé, Frederic (re: letter of thanks for assistance with research) (Box 48)
  - Vancouver Women’s Caucus (Box 48)
  - Van den Dungen, Peter (reference: pacifist literature) (Box 48)
  - Vandersypen, Karla (Box 48)
  - Vandervort, Bruce (reference: Victor Griffuelhes; CGT; post-WWI anarcho-syndicalist movements) (Box 48)
  - Van Dyke, Henry (1 - 7 of 12 folders) (Box 48)
  - Van Dyke, Henry (8 - 12 of 12 folders) (Box 49)
  - Vanguard (London) (Box 49)
  - Vanguard Books (Chicago) (Box 49)
  - Van Ingen, Patricia (re: sale of books to LC) (Box 49)
  - Van Liew, Donald (Box 49)
  - Van Notten, Eleanore (reference: Harlem Renaissance; Wallace Thurman) (Box 49)
  - Van Vechten, Carl (Box 49)
  - Van Wienen, Mark (reference: American protest poetry of WWI—no written reply) (Box 49)
  - Vash, Ernest (Box 49)
  - Vector Magazine (San Francisco, CA) (Box 49)
  - Vega-Byrnes, Thomas (Box 49)
  - Veleker, Wilma Haywood (reference: William D. Haywood) (Box 49)
  - Velvet Fist, The (Toronto, Canada) (Box 49)
  - Venable, Alan (reference: Homestead Strike) (Box 49)
  - Venceremos Brigade (New York) (Box 49)
  - Venning, Philip (reference: Charlotte Wilson) (Box 49)
  - Ventana, Gay (Bogotá, Colombia) (Box 49)
  - Ventura, Gracia (re: thank you note from ECW for donation to LC) (Box 49)
  - Verlag Detlev Auverman KG (reference: Fanal; Rundbrief) (Box 49)
  - Vetsel, Judy (Box 49)
  - Veysey, Laurence R. (reference: anarchism; Ferrer Modern School; Stelton) (Box 49)
  - Vial, Rebecca (reference: Kate Bradford Stockton) (Box 49)
  - Viet/nam Bulletinen (Stockholm, Sweden) (Box 49)
  - Vietnam International, see International Conf. for Disarmament and Peace (Box 49)
  - Vilanova, Antonio (reference: underground activities of Spanish political refugees during WWII) (Box 49)
  - Village Voice, The (New York) (Box 49)
  - Vitó (Curacao, West Indies) (Box 49)
  - Viva Eu (Sao Paulo, Brazil) (Box 49)
  - Vivancos, Eduardo (re: letter from ECW—no reply) (Box 49)
  - Vocations for Social Change (Box 49)
  - Voelker, Don (reference: Wadsworth Manufacturing Co. strike of 1919) (Box 49)
  - Vogel, Virgil J. (re: Tad Tekla) (Box 50)
  - Voice of Liberty (Decatur, Georgia) (Box 50)
  - Voice of the Black Community (Decatur, Illinois) (Box 50)
  - Voice of the Women’s Liberation Movement (Chicago) (Box 50)
  - Voland, Joseph F. (reference: IWW) (Box 50)
  - Von Holdt, Bob (re: ECW inquiry about The Movement) (Box 50)
  - Voss, Edward (re: donations to LC) (Box 50)
  - Voz Chicana, La (San Juan, Texas) (Box 50)
  - Voz Proletaria (Buenos Aires, Argentina) (Box 50)
  - Voz Socialista (Caracas, Venezuela) (Box 50)
  - Vyverberg, Henry (5 folders) (Box 50)
  - Wachsberger, Ken (Box 50)
  - Wade, Harry (reference: John Francis Bray) (Box 50)
  - Wagman, Frederick (re: letter from ECW about Elizabeth Gurley Flynn) (Box 50)
  - Wagner, Janet (reference: Josiah Warren; Stephen Pearl Andrews; Modern Times) (Box 50)
  - Wagner, Steve (re: publisher of Appeal to Reason and Seattle Sexual Freedom League Bulletin) (Box 50)
  - Wald, Alan (Box 50)
  - Walden, Eleanor (reference: Armistice Day; Centralia, Wash.) (Box 50)
  - Walk a Crooked Mile Books (reference: T.E. Lawrence letter to James Handley) (Box 50)
  - Walker, Bill/IALGAL (reference: LGBT publications and general inquiry about LC) (Box 50)
  - Wallach, Bill (re: LC grant proposal to NEH) (Box 50)
  - Walsh, James (re: bibliography of SDS publications) (Box 50)
  - Walsh, James P. (reference: Vincent Hallinan) (Box 50)
  - Walter, Karl & Bertha (re: ECW request for Karl’s book, Many Maternities) (Box 50)
  - Walter, Nicolas (reference: Kropotkin’s Paroles d’un Révolté; Alarm) (Box 50)
  - Walter, Scott (reference: free school movement of 1960s-70s; Youth Liberation, etc.) (Box 50)
  - Wanderer, The (St. Paul, MN) (Box 50)
  - WAP-World Information Exchange (LC letter requesting materials) (Box 50)
  - War and Peace Foundation (reference: request for exhibit materials; Rosika Schwimmer) (Box 50)
  - War/Peace Report (New York, NY) (Box 50)
  - War Resisters’ International (London, England) (Box 50)
  - War Resister League (New York, NY) (Box 50)
  - Ward, Fritz (reference: Laurance Labadie) (Box 50)
  - Warfield, Gregory (reference: extreme right wing press; KKK; American Nazi Party; John Birch; etc.) (Box 50)
  - Warford, William S., Rev. (reference: Joe Hill) (Box 50)
  - Warren, Lyman (re: loan—and return of [Josiah] Warren family bible and Winships Historical Brighton) (Box 50)
  - Warsaw Voice (Box 51)
  - Was Tun (West Germany) (Box 51)
  - Washington Blade (Box 51)
  - Washington (State) Dept. of Corrections (re: ECW inquiry of Carl Harp) (Box 51)
  - Washington State Historical Society (reference: Utopian colony newspapers; Ralph Chaplin) (Box 51)
  - Washington State Library (reference: Utopian colony newspapers; Lois Waisbrooker; Home colony) (Box 51)
  - Wasserman, Harvey (reference: The Masses; Mother Earth) (Box 51)
  - Water Tunnel (State College, PA) (Box 51)
  - Watner, Carl (reference: various anarchist topics) (Box 51)
  - Watson, David (Box 51)
  - Watson, William (reference: to Curator William Barkley; IWW; Ralph Chaplin’s poems) (Box 51)
  - Watts, Theodore (re: indexing of New Masses; Anvil; Liberator, etc. also some letters from ECW describing health issues) (Box 51)
  - Way, Steward (reference: Rebel Song Book; Agnes Inglis; Michigan Socialist House—1930s) (Box 51)
  - Wayne State University, African American Educational Archives (re: survey of oral history sources) (Box 51)
  - Wayne State University, German-American Bibliographic Guide Project (re: survey of materials) (Box 51)
  - Wayne State University, Reuther Library (Box 51)
  - Wayne State University, Purdy-Kresge Library (loan of materials to LC for exhibit) (Box 51)
  - W.E.B. Dubois Clubs of America (Box 51)
  - Weaver, Mollly (re: Great Labor Arts Exchange) (Box 51)
  - Weber, David E. (reference: James W. Ford; Negro Worker) (Box 51)
  - Weber, David M. (reference: New Left; SDS;Tom Hayden; Port Huron Statement) (Box 51)
  - Weber, Edward C. (2 folders) (Box 51)
  - Weber, Joanne (Box 51)
  - Weber, S. (Box 51)
  - Webster, J. R. (reference: anarchist publications 1925-1936) (Box 51)
  - Webster, Paul M. (reference: permission for copy of Augustin Souchy manuscript) (Box 51)
  - Weekly Crusader (Tulsa, OK) (Box 51)
  - Weihs, Ron (reference: writing play about IWW; Don Stewart) (Box 51)
  - Weik, Mrs. Mary Hays (re: sending Window on the World to LC) (Box 51)
  - Weine, Seth Joseph (reference: looking for rare pamphlet: Sodom in Union Square) (Box 51)
  - Weiner, Lynn (reference: wants to make a poster of Emma Goldman photograph) (Box 51)
  - Weinrich, Peter (reference: bibliography of radical movements in Canada 1870-1975) (Box 51)
  - Weintraub, Hy (reference: Andrew Furuseth) (Box 51)
  - Weir, Stan (reference: Longshore Jobs Defense Committee; Bayard Rustin; Mike Harrington) (Box 51)
  - Weis, James A. (reference: Gerald L.K. Smith) (Box 51)
  - Weisberg, Harold (re: sale of books about JFK assassination) (Box 51)
  - Weisert, John J. (reference: Karl Heinzen; Janus; Der Pionier) (Box 51)
  - Weissborn, Henry (re: response to LC inquiry from IWW, Houston, TX branch) (Box 51)
  - Weissman, Gordy (Box 51)
  - Weller, Ken (re: birth of socialist movement 1880-1900; Laurence Gronlund) (Box 52)
  - Wellman, Saul (re: donation of his pamphlet collection on Spanish Civil War (Box 52)
  - Wells, Ruth L. (re: worked in LC with Agnes Inglis; donated scrapbook and other materials) (Box 52)
  - Wellesley Historical Society (re: Denton family papers) (Box 52)
  - Weltner, Charles L., State Rep. (re: ECW request for KKK materials) (Box 52)
  - Wendt, Matthias (reference: J. William Lloyd) (Box 52)
  - Wenzer, Kenneth C. (reference: Alexander Berkman) (Box 52)
  - Werkheiser, Don (re: donation of his papers to LC) (Box 52)
  - Werly, John M. (reference: American right-wing movements; William Dudley Pelley) (Box 52)
  - Werntz, Ted (reference: American Labor Union; Herman Richter) (Box 52)
  - West End Catholic Worker (re: Mutual Aid) (Box 52)
  - Westacott, Jane (re: thank you for tour of LC) (Box 52)
  - Western Destiny (Los Angeles, CA) (Box 52)
  - Western Maritime Press (Box 52)
  - Western Review Institute (Box 52)
  - Western Socialist (Detroit, MI) (Box 52)
  - Western Voice (Vancouver, BC) (Box 52)
  - Wexler, Alice R. (reference: Emma Goldman; Max Baginski) (Box 52)
  - Wheatley, Robert H. (re: access to his “The Value of the Labadie Collection of the University of Michigan to the Study of the Spanish Civil War”) (Box 52)
  - Wheeler, Bernard L. (re: seeking a copy of Free Vistas) (Box 52)
  - Whitcomb, John M. (reference: IWW; Mathew Schmidt; Ernest Unterman; Chicago trial) (Box 52)
  - White, Lula M. (reference: IWW; Lawrence strike 1912) (Box 52)
  - White, Scoop (reference: International Typographical Union records) (Box 52)
  - White American (Birmingham, AL) (Box 52)
  - White Nationalist Newsletter (Asheville, NC) (Box 52)
  - White Panther Party (letter signed by Genie Plamondon) (Box 52)
  - Whitehead, Fred (includes letter of support from ECW) (Box 52)
  - Whitesell, David (former employee) (Box 52)
  - Who Killed Kennedy Committee (London) (Box 52)
  - Wicklund, Alfred (reference: The Socialist Voice-Oakland, CA) (Box 52)
  - Wiethoff, William E. (reference: Elizabeth Gurley Flynn; Patterson Strike) (Box 52)
  - Wilcock, John (re: his publication Other Scenes) (Box 52)
  - Wilcox, Laird (re: his Directory of the American Right) (Box 52)
  - Wilder, Una (re: Maxwell Reade; E. Haldeman-Julius; Dillingham collection of LBBs) (Box 52)
  - Will, Thomas E. (reference: a young person looking for books about anarchism) (Box 52)
  - Willard, Tim (reference: Toledo Auto Lite Strike of 1934) (Box 52)
  - William Winters Comments (Los Angeles, CA) (re: exchange of letters with Nancy Flowers) (Box 52)
  - Williams, Joyce (reference: Victoria Woodhull; Josiah Warren) (Box 52)
  - Wilmington 10 Defense Committee (Box 52)
  - Wilson, Ann Bentley (reference: IWW; Paterson strike of 1913) (Box 52)
  - Wiltz, John Edward (reference: 19th century American anarchism) (Box 52)
  - Win Magazine (New York) (Box 52)
  - Wind and Chaff (New York) (Box 52)
  - Winkelmann, Edward (reference: Johann Most) (Box 52)
  - Winslow, Gordon W. (reference: Cuban newspapers Libertad and Tiempo) (Box 52)
  - Winters, Donald E., Jr. (reference: IWW; American religion in the Progressive Era; Minnesota’s Iron Range) (Box 52)
  - Wisconsin Gas Co. (reference: articles about how to steal gas in YIPL and TAP) (Box 52)
  - Wisconsin State Historical Society (Box 52)
  - Wisconsin Women Library Workers (reference: photo of Agnes Inglis for their postcard series) (Box 52)
  - Wise, Judith (re: suggests radical publications for LC— Arm the Spirit, Wildcat, Clash) (Box 52)
  - Wisenberg, Sandi (Box 52)
  - Wisotsky, Isidore (re: autobiography sent to LC) (Box 52)
  - Wixson, Douglas (reference: little magazine and proletarian publications of the 1920s) (Box 52)
  - Wobbly (Berkeley, CA) (Box 52)
  - Wolf, Sam (reference: British and French anarchist movements) (Box 52)
  - Women’s History Research Center (Berkeley, CA) (Box 52)
  - Woman’s World (New York, NY) (Box 52)
  - Women: A Journal of Liberation (Baltimore, MD) (Box 52)
  - Women Now (Supersedes Socialist Women) (Nottingham, England) (Box 52)
  - Wood Heat Quarterly (Wolcott, VT) (Box 52)
  - Woodford, Arthur (reference: photos of Joseph Labadie and Richard Trevellick) (Box 52)
  - Woodstock Anarchist Party (Sydney, Australia) (Box 52)
  - Woodworth, Fred (Box 52)
  - Worcester Punch (Worcester, MA) (Box 52)
  - Wordsworth, Gerard (Box 52)
  - Worker, The (New York, NY) (Box 52)
  - Worker’s Democracy (St. Louis, MO) (quotes Lenin regarding librarians) (Box 52)
  - Workers News Service (Ewa Beach, HI) (Box 52)
  - Workers Press (London, England) (Box 53)
  - Workers Solidarity Movement (Dublin, Ireland) (Box 53)
  - Workers Vanguard (Toronto, Ontario) (Box 53)
  - Workers Viewpoint (New York, NY) (Box 53)
  - Workers World (New York, NY) (Box 53)
  - Workforce (see also: Vocations for Social Change) (Box 53)
  - Workmen’s Circle, The (New York) (Box 53)
  - World Association of World Federalists (Box 53)
  - World Federalist Youth, USA (Box 53)
  - World Prophetic Ministry (Box 53)
  - World Revolution (Progressive Labor Party) (Box 53)
  - World to Win (San Francisco, CA) (Box 53)
  - Wortman, Roy (reference: IWW; Paul Sebastyen; Toledo 1919 strike; E.S.Rose) (Box 53)
  - Wreszin, Michael (reference: Dwight MacDonald; B.J. Widdick) (Box 53)
  - Wuest, Florence (Box 53)
  - Wunderlich, Roger (reference: Josiah Warren) (Box 53)
  - Wutke, Eugene R. (reference: Technical Alliance) (Box 53)
  - Wye, Christopher G. (reference: The Negro in Cleveland during Depression and War years) (Box 53)
  - Wyman, Mark (reference: Western Federation of Miners (Box 53)
  - Xerox University Microfilms (re: microfilming of The Black Panther and Los Angeles Free Press) (Box 53)
  - Yanosky, Ronald (reference: Henry George) (Box 53)
  - Yashima, Yukari (reference: Spanish Civil War) (Box 53)
  - Yaswan, Gordon (Box 53)
  - Yearley, C. K. (reference: Richard Trevellick; Peter Kropotkin) (Box 53)
  - Yelensky, Boris (re: donation of Sunrise Cooperative papers) (Box 53)
  - Yoffe, Mark (re: setting up international counterculture archive at GWU) (Box 53)
  - Young, Allen (re: wrote book about treatment of gays in Cuba) (Box 53)
  - Young, Gordon (Box 53)
  - Young, John (reference: seeking info on grandfather’s union membership) (Box 53)
  - Young Americans for Freedom (Box 53)
  - Young Guard (London) (Box 53)
  - Young Lords’ Party (Box 53)
  - Young People’s Socialist League (Box 53)
  - Young Socialist (Ceylon, Sri Lanka) (Box 53)
  - Young Socialist (New York) (Box 53)
  - Young Socialist (Toronto) (Box 53)
  - Young Socialist Forum (New York) (Box 53)
  - Youth Action News (Alexandria, VA) (Box 53)
  - Youth Against War and Fascism (New York) (Box 53)
  - Youth Liberation (Ann Arbor, MI) (Box 53)
  - Zabawa, Bruce M. (Box 53)
  - Zakrzewski, Karl (reference: Spanish Civil War) (Box 53)
  - Zane, David (Box 53)
  - Zanger, Martin (reference: Upton Sinclair’s role in 1923 IWW maritime strike in San Pedro, CA) (Box 53)
  - Zanjani, Sally S. (reference: Nevada Socialist Party 1890-1920) (Box 53)
  - Zapata Books (reference: various U.S. left wing publications, 1940s-1970s) (Box 53)
  - Zavala, Iris M. (reference: Spanish Thought in the 18th and 19th centuries) (Box 53)
  - Zero Population Growth (Box 53)
  - Zilber, Jacob (reference: IWW trials of Thomas Tracy and Britt Smith) (Box 53)
  - Zimbabwe Review (Box 53)
  - Zimmerman, Roy W. (reference: Josiah Warren) (Box 53)
  - Zinn, Roslyn (reference: Women political prisoners of 19th and 20th centuries) (Box 53)
  - Zonderman, David A. (reference: Karl Heinzen, Ezra Heywood, Josiah Warren) (Box 53)
  - Zubal, John T. (book dealer) (Box 53)
  - Zube, John (contains microfiche) (Box 53)
  - Zukowski, Jenny (thank you to ECW) (Box 53)
  - Zuleta Ruiz, Leon/Movimento de Liberacion Homosexual (Colombia) (Box 53)
  - Zweiback, Timothy (reference: wants microfilm of “The Detroit Labor press 1839-1899”) (Box 53)
  - Zwieg, Arnulf (personal friend of ECW) ( 2 folders) (Box 53)
  - Unidentified correspondents (Box 54)
- Realia
  - Framed commendations (Oversize 55 (o.s.))